

Names and surnames: Sebastian Francisco Ponce Vidal

Date of birth: 21.07.1982

I.D.: 8485641 issued in Puerto Colombia, Atlantico

Personal and professional skills.

Committed professional, honest person, very responsible and qualified, capable of fulfilling my job under pressure. Computer Science Engineer graduated from the "Universidad del Norte" in Barranquilla, Colombia, 2005. Specialized in Database Development at the Jorge Tadeo Lozano University of Bogota, 2007. Certified as OCA by Oracle 9i (2008). I'm currently studying to get the Java Certification 11 by myself.

Experience in Software

Level	Products/ Technologies / Methodologies
Expert	Oracle PL/SQL, Oracle SQL, Java v8 and v11, JSP, Toad, Q-Manager, Jdeveloper, Oracle SQL Developer.
Advanced	Visual C++, GUI Design, MySQL, Eclipse, NetBeans, Android, Beyond Compare, GIT, IntelliJ Idea
Intermediate	Oracle Forms Developer, Javascript, Azure
Basic	Visual Basic, XML, JSF, SpringBoot

Academic Background

07/2007 - 11/2008 Oracle Technology Network and Compuclub Center, Bogotá, Colombia.

Certified as OCA Developer PL/SQL

Description/Comments

This certificate exam consists of evaluation the Oracle Development Platform. The evaluation includes two other exams that are required in order to achieve the official certificate.

·

01/2006 - 04/2007 Unviersidad de Bogotá Jorge Tadeo Lozano, Bogotá, Colombia.

Specialist in Database Development.

Description/Comments

This specialization is focused on Database design, development, analysis and administration based on the Oracle Tools, as well as the application of other Database tools.

01/2000 – 10/2005 Universidad del Norte, Barranquilla, Colombia.

Systems Engineer

Description/Comments

Professional Studies - Undergraduate.

Work Experience

02/2017- 11/2022

Inforcol S.A. –Liberty Insurances Colombia. Confianza Re-Swiss Insurances. Seguros Positiva.

Senior Development Analyst

Description/Comments

- Analysis and Development of Insurances Oracle and Java, J2EE interfaces oriented to satisfaction of user requirements.
- Trainning to new professionals about the use of iAxis application and database development itself
- Scrum Master organization to solve doubts in the development and to carry out programming best practices.
- Development of tasks inside on iAxis from Confianza insurances under Oracle and Java tools.
- Support and Management of Re-insurance issues through the tool Jira.
- Analysis and Development of requirements on iAxis tool for Seguros Positiva, the insurance company of the State in the modules Issuing, Renovation and Re-insurance.
- Configuration of insurance products in Mapfre Brazil through Oracle SQL, Java and Jira.

04/2015 - 11/2016

Indepedent Java Android and Oracle Consultant.

Consultant.

Description/Comments

- Desing and Development of software on Visual C++ and Oracle PL/SQL for an airline in USA.
- Test and Implementation of the System
- Android Development for Entertaiment for Adults.
- Development of Alarms for Smartphones with Android Technology.

03/2013 - 04/2015

4Sight Technologies. Mapfre USA.

Senior Engineer.

Description/Comments

- Analysis and Development of the requirements set for the Tronweb Project focused on the development plan of Mapfre, MA, USA.
- Development and Management focused on Claims and Treasury modules.
- Support on production incidences for all companies of Mapfre USA.
- Analysis of java interfaces of Tronweb module for improvement of processes.
- Basic analysis of queries that require tunning.

02/2012 - 03/2013

Indra Company Colombia. Mapfre Latinoamerica.

Software Engineer.

Description/Comments

- Analysis and Development of the requirements set for the Tronweb Project focused on the development plan of Mapfre in Peru,
- Development and Management focused on the core applications made for Mapfre Peru, Spain and Mexico.
- Analysis of java interfaces of Tronweb module for improvement of processes.
- Management of Java object to integrate in Quality Environments.

07/2011 - 01/2012

Unidad de Malla Vial.

Support Engineer - HelpDesk.

Description/Comments

- Analysis as applicable to the PREDIS application from the SICAPITAL module for the management of the budget of the interested entity.
- Support and Development of Applications in Oracle Developer 10g (Oracle Forms, Oracle Reports and PL/SQL)
- Updating of the information about the schemes for users in accordance with transactions for this year.

03/2011 - 07/2011

Mainsoft Ltda. Legis Colombia

Process and Test Engineer

Description/Comments

- Training in order to work Legis offices, as well as in order to know the Oracle Developer 6i environment.
- Research of new technologies and paradigms in order to provide better software solutions in the companies.

05/2010 - 12/2010

Inforcol S.A.- Mapfre Colombia

Information Analyst

Description/Comments

- Analysis and Development of the requirements for the Java Tronweb system platform in order to manage insurance business at Mapfre.
- Development management in production environments

06/2009 - 08/2009

Banco AV Villas.

Analyst I.

Description/Comments

- Developments of reports and stored procedures for Human Resources software under J2EE tools and Jasper Reports.
- Support of requirements of Human Resource Area over Java classes and interfaces.

Languages

English	Speaking: Fluently Writing: Excellent
Spanish	Spaking: Native Writing: Native
Portuguese	Speaking: Basic Writing: Basic
French	Speaking: Basic Wrtitng: Basic

Contact Information:

Land line (Domicile): (57 1) 8078704 Cell phone: Email: Skype:

(57 1) 3174321244
sebastianfranciscoponcevidal@gmail.com
seponce19@hotmail.com.
https://www.linkedin.com/in/sebasti%C3%A1n-ponce-5235ab35 LinkedIn: